The end of the world is just the tip of the iceberg.
Ice Age: Continental Drift is a animation, comedy,
adventure film directed by Steve Martino.
Manny, Diego, and Sid embark upon another adventure
after their continent is set adrift.
Using an iceberg as a ship, they encounter sea creatures and
battle pirates as they explore a new world.
Manny (voice), played by Ray Romano.
Sid (voice), played by John Leguizamo.
Diego (voice), played by Denis Leary.
Crash (voice), played by Seann William Scott.
Eddie (voice), played by Josh Peck.
Ellie (voice), played by Queen Latifah.
Ice Age: Continental Drift is a 2012 American animated
adventure comedy film produced by Blue Sky Studios.
The fourth in the Ice Age film series, it was directed by Steve Martino and
Michael Thurmeier and written by Michael Berg and Jason Fuchs.
Ray Romano, John Leguizamo, Denis Leary and Queen Latifah reprise their roles from the
previous films, with Jennifer Lopez, Drake, and Nicki Minaj joining the cast.
The film involves Scrat mistakenly sending Manny, Sid, and Diego adrift on an iceberg with
Sid's Granny, leading them to face a gang of pirates led by Captain Gutt.
The film premiered at CineEurope on June 20, 2012, and was theatrically
released in the United States on July 13 by 20th Century Fox.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $877 million worldwide, making it the
fifth highest-grossing film and the highest-grossing animated film of 2012.
A further sequel, Ice Age: Collision Course, was released in 2016.
The film explores themes of villain, sequel,
prehistory, seal (animal), aftercreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted.